▍2026 美网 女单1/4决赛
莱巴金娜 3-6 6-1 6-4 郑钦文 · 赛后场上采访
Elena, congratulations for the first time
埃琳娜 恭喜你首次
into the semi -final of the US Open,
闯入美网半决赛
and on Monday,
而且到了周一
when the new ranking comes out, you
新排名公布时 你
will be officially the new world number one
将正式成为新的世界第一
in women's tennis.
在女子网坛
What does it all mean to you, Elena?
这一切意味着什么 埃琳娜？
It's tough to find words.
很难用言语形容
It's been very difficult match, and honestly,
比赛非常艰难 说实话
a lot of nerves, of course, and yeah,
当然非常紧张 没错
it wasn't maybe the highest level,
也许没打出最高水平
but I'm glad that I pushed
但很高兴我坚持了下来
through, and thank you so much guys
也非常感谢大家
for coming, supporting.
来现场支持我
It's been an early match. In my head,
比赛很早 我脑子里
I was complaining a little bit about the sun,
我有点抱怨阳光
shadow, a lot of things.
阴影 还有很多事情
It was definitely a battle inside me,
我内心确实打了一仗
but I'm glad that I pushed all
但很高兴我排开了
the negative thoughts away,
所有负面想法
and I kept on fighting, and yeah, again,
继续拼搏 再说一次
super happy to be in the semi -final here.
很开心打进这里的半决赛
Not only in the semis, but also
不只是打进四强
on the world number one on Monday.
周一还将成为世界第一
Do you think about it
你会想到这件事吗
when you are playing the match?
在你比赛的时候？
You came back from a set down,
你从落后一盘追了回来
you saved break points in the third set.
决胜盘还救了破发点
What kept you going in these moments,
那些时刻什么让你坚持
and what kept you so strong
又是什么让你如此坚强
in these important moments?
在这些关键时刻？
Yeah, as I said, I didn't start that well,
是的 如我所说 开局不好
and I was too much negative,
我当时太消极了
and also it wasn't easy
而且确实不容易
because all the matches here I played
因为之前这里所有比赛
at night, and I was scheduled
我都在晚上打 原本安排
to play once in the morning,
有一次在早上打
but then it was raining, so basically it's
但后来下雨了 所以算是
been the first match like this on the sun,
首次在这样的阳光下比赛
so yeah, it was a lot of unforced errors,
所以有很多非受迫性失误
but then I just was telling myself,
后来我一直告诉自己
keep on fighting, keep on working
继续拼搏 继续努力
on some things, and yeah, luckily,
调整一些东西 幸运的是
it went my way, and I'm just super happy.
结果如我所愿 我很开心
You played so well, I will let you go soon.
打得真好 很快就放你走
Now, milestone is achieved,
现在这个里程碑已达成
you are world number one.
你是世界第一
How will you try and stay focused?
你会怎样保持专注？
There are two more matches to be played.
还有两场比赛要打
What will be your mental approach
你会怎样调整心态
in the next two days, hopefully, for you?
接下来的两天 但愿如此
Well, it's just a number right now,
此刻这只是一个数字
and of course, I'm in the semi,
当然 我已经进入四强
so my goal is to win the tournaments
我的目标是赢下赛事
which I play, and I go just match at a time,
我参加的赛事 一场场来
and it's an amazing achievement,
这是了不起的成就
but you know how quick everything
但你知道一切变化多快
can change in tennis, ranking wise,
在网球中 排名也会变
during the match, so I feel like I just need
比赛中也一样 我需要
to focus on my game, try to recover,
专注自己的球 努力恢复
and enjoy tomorrow.
然后享受明天
Congratulations, Elena, into the semi -finals,
恭喜埃琳娜 打进半决赛
Elena Rybakina.
埃琳娜 莱巴金娜